<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COSN_Terry | Chinese Open Science Network</title>
    <link>https://terryzang.github.io/author/cosn_terry/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://terryzang.github.io/author/cosn_terry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>COSN_Terry</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://terryzang.github.io/media/icon_hu_c1867564a64e758d.png</url>
      <title>COSN_Terry</title>
      <link>https://terryzang.github.io/author/cosn_terry/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive interview with the editor-in-chief of eLife</title>
      <link>https://terryzang.github.io/about/post/2025-5-elife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://terryzang.github.io/about/post/2025-5-elife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive interview with the editor-in-chief of eLife: Without the impact factor, the number of submissions from China has decreased by 80%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In November 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, Clarivate announced that the eLife journal would no longer be assigned an SCI impact factor. Previously, this interdisciplinary biology journal had an IF of 6.4. As of 2025, this pioneering open-access journal began to feel the aftershocks of losing the impact factor, and &amp;ldquo;the biggest and most significant changes all came from China.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Timothy Behrens, the editor-in-chief of eLife, is the deputy director of the Wellcome Centre for Integrative Neuroimaging at the University of Oxford, a professor of computational neurobiology, and an honorary lecturer at University College London. He disclosed to the intellectuals: &amp;ldquo;(Before the decision of Clarivate Analytics)&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;About 40% of the submissions to eLife came from China. Now, we have lost approximately 80% of the submissions from China.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This non-profit academic journal was established in 2012 and is supported by three powerful scientific funding institutions in the United States (Howard Hughes Medical Institute), the United Kingdom (Wellcome Foundation), and Germany (Max Planck Society). The founding editor was Randy Schekman, a 2012 Nobel Prize winner. eLife is renowned for its pioneering and experimental publishing model. After winning the Nobel Prize, Randy Schekman publicly criticized top journals such as CNS (Cell, Science, Nature), saying they were like &amp;ldquo;limited luxury goods&amp;rdquo;, causing unnecessary pressure on scientists.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-elife-logo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://terryzang.github.io/images/post/20250730.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;eLife Logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      eLife Logo
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From its inception, in addition to open access, another significant innovation of eLife was the collaborative system for peer review, which means that the reviewers and the editors discuss the opinions together. This concept attracted dozens of active scientists to serve as editors, responsible for screening the submissions, and hundreds of scientists to serve as reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
